Saif Kbishi

052-6901487 | saifkbishi@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Github

Summary:

FullStack Web Developer with experience in **JavaScript**, **React**, **NodeJs**, **React Native**. As a former Technical Support Engineer with **BS.c. in Software Engineering** - I'm driven to project my skills in **solving problems** into the software world.

Experience:

2021 A coding project for Appleseeds

- Transforming the platform from AngularJS to React, examining the former portal design, API calls & responses testing them in Postman
- Developing better components utilizing React library and Material-UI framework.

2013- 2020 Technical Support Engineer - SeatGeek Inc

- Design ticketing sites and landing pages based on client requirements, using JS, CSS, HTML.
- Setup and maintain client's env. On Netvision, self-hosted and **AWS servers** activate application channels.
- Install and support third-party integrations ie. Passbook, Facebook SSO app, Sports Alliance SSO, Paypal, Queue-it.
- Write and execute **SQL** data fixes on **MSSQL** test/production DB.
- Provide support to our worldwide client for our ticketing SaaS
- ✓ I have reduced the number of JIRA TKTs forwarded to Web and Core teams by 30%.

2011-2013 QA tester, Qualitest. Microsoft Project, Personal Data Dashboard website

Performing manual tests on web applications along with writing QA STD, STP, STR.

Education:

2021 - Full Stack JavaScript Bootcamp graduate - Appleseeds Academy

Intensive 6-months, 720 hours training program that encourages self-led learning and group projects that simulate real-world development teams. Learning and applying the **MERN** stack.

2013 B.Sc in Software engineering, Ort Braude Karmiel

2012 CCNA Network Management course graduate - CISCO

2011 QA graduate - Qualitest: ISTQB, networks, STR, STD, STP

Coding Project:

MyBalance - a MERN fullstack (MongoDB, Express, ReactJs, NodeJs) CRUD application.

The back-end **server** uses Node.js + Express for **REST API**s, the front-end side is a React client with **React Router**, **Axios** & **Bootstrap**. **Bcrypt** for user authentication, to keep track of daily expenses.

Computer skills and technologies:

Programming languages: React, MongoDB, React Native, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap, MySql,

JQuery, TypeScript, Jest, MsSQL, Python.

Other technologies: Github, AWS, Heroku, JIRA, SalesForce, Docker.

Military Service: 2002-2006: Duty service in the Artillery Corps, released as Lieutenant.

<u>Volunteering:</u> **2008-2012:** working with youth in "Aharai Lezahal" (אחרי לצה"ל). <u>Languages:</u> Arabic - native; Hebrew – highly Proficient; English - proficient.